Hi, I'm Stan DeFreitas, Mr. Green Thumb for On Gardening.
One of the most important elements of all plants is nitrogen.
Nitrogen is always always the first number on the bag or on the bottle.
It will usually be NPNK.
The first number is Nitrogen.
Why is it important?
Well Nitrogen helps your plant to grow.
It is the green and growing element.
If you want your little plant to get up and grow you want to make sure it has a good source of Nitrogen.
This particular bottle has 9 % Nitrogen and you see it happens to be Ammoniacal Nitrogen which is okay.
This may leak out quicker than some other sources of nitrogen but it is still a pretty readily source and it will be used in water and of course remember that is where plants have to absorb the nutrients.
So Nitrogen the first number is an element that is going to give you green and grow.
If you ever look at some of the lawn foods they are normally higher in that first number.